Thor Wessel Lindberg

Reykjavík, Iceland thor@lindberg.is lindberg.is

linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg



Profile

M.Sc. Design specialized in UX and Healthcare, with an interdisciplinary background in medical science, information technology and user-centred design. Through working as a Consultant I have become versed in managing and mediating clients, as I collaborated with multi-national teams on both Java backend software and a React Native application.

I spend my spare time continuously learning, building software, experimenting with new technologies, and traveling through the United States to network with others in the technology sector.

Education

IT University of Copenhagen

08/2020 — 06/2022

Master of Science in Digital Design

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

• Explorative design for embedding typed objects in JSON.

Relevant courses:

 React Native mobile development with Expo, UX Design, Advanced Design Processes.

Copenhagen University

08/2017 — 07/2020

Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

 Qualitative analysis to determine potential low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims, within economic constraints of the Danish healthcare system.

Relevant courses:

 Statistics, Mathematical Modelling, Medical Image Analysis, IT Security, Interaction Design, Programming for Biosciences, Human Anatomy and Physiology.

Experience

Netcompany

08/2022 - 12/2023

IT Consultant

- Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, managing project timeline and tasks.
- Analyzed and documented existing business processes on 2 projects for 2 clients.
- Analyzed IT-infrastructure and digital transformation strategy on 2 projects for 2 clients.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- Contributed to source code optimization and adding features to React Native frontend application.

National Special Crime Unit

10/2021 - 07/2022

IT-Administrative Student

- Managed users of webportal and provided direct support for reporting suspicion of financial crime.
- · Authored documentation and website content.

IT University of Copenhagen

08/2021 - 06/2022

Teaching Assistant

 Assisted with teaching courses in Python, JavaScript with MQTT, and UX Design specialization.

Domino's Pizza

08/2021 - 01/2022

Shift Leader

 Responsible for closing store, delegating work, managing cash, and primary pizza baker.

Skills

Fluent in English and Danish. Beginner at Icelandic

Design in Figma with components, variants, flows, auto layout

Frontend software in React Native, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI

Data analysis with Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Data processing with Visual Basic for Applications (VBA)

Published

Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland

App Store

apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299